<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-19T17:48:39-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Victor Chen</title><subtitle>Just weaving my little corner of the web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Eulogy Virtues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2026/02/14/The-Eulogy-Virtues.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Eulogy Virtues" /><published>2026-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2026-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2026/02/14/The%20Eulogy%20Virtues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2026/02/14/The-Eulogy-Virtues.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I’ve been thinking a lot about how I should adjust the way I treat people.</p>

<p>I once wrote that life moves quickly, and that I’ve already lived through a third of it. I want to experience as many emotions as I can, both the beautiful ones and the painful ones. Because of that, I try to give my all in everything I do, especially when it comes to the people around me. I like that version of myself.</p>

<p>But in doing so, I sometimes hear things I never expected. Some people think I do too much. Some wonder if my kindness means I like someone. Some tell me that love should be measured and given in proportion. Sometimes it even begins to affect my own life. I always try to find reasons for them. I choose to believe they are kind, because if I were them, I would want someone to treat me that way too.</p>

<p>There are moments when I wonder if I’m trying too hard to be a kind of superhero, believing I can endlessly give love to the people around me, while forgetting that the weight I carry keeps growing heavier.</p>

<p>Over these past few days, I’ve come to realize that this is simply who I am. Maybe the answer is to keep doing what feels true to me. No matter how others interpret it, no matter how they respond to my sincerity, as long as I can say I acted without regret, that is enough. And perhaps someday, if we drift apart, they might still remember how it felt. Maybe a small trace of warmth will remain. Maybe that alone is enough.</p>

<p>In Seattle, I’ve noticed how many people care deeply about their job titles, their status, and how much they earn. Some begin to see themselves as above others, forgetting gratitude and don’t care about other people. Every time I see it, it feels strangely hollow. Strip away the labels, and there is nothing left that truly defines who they are.</p>

<p>I want to always remember this: Never sacrifice eulogy virtues in the pursuit of resume virtues. To keep doing what I believe is right. To give what I can give. To remain someone with a soul.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I’ve been thinking a lot about how I should adjust the way I treat people.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Excuses vs. Barriers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2026/02/03/Excuses-vs.-Barriers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Excuses vs. Barriers" /><published>2026-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2026-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2026/02/03/Excuses%20vs.%20Barriers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2026/02/03/Excuses-vs.-Barriers.html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I’ve spoken with a few people, and reflecting on their experiences—and my own—made one thing clear: if you want the life you truly want, you have to keep asking yourself hard questions.</p>

<p>One person said they were too lazy to apply for a position. But why not start somewhere and improve along the way? Why not treat it as practice? Why not use it to strengthen your other opportunities? Often, the cost of trying is small, while the potential gain is huge. Avoiding it entirely usually reflects fear more than laziness.</p>

<p>Another person said they failed interviews because they need sponsorship. But if a company truly avoids candidates who need sponsorship, they likely wouldn’t even grant a first interview. So is sponsorship really the full reason for rejection? Or is there something you could still improve for next time? Treating every rejection as an external constraint quietly stops growth. Seize every opportunity to learn and improve.</p>

<p>Someone else said they couldn’t find the motivation to apply for an exchange program. If money isn’t the barrier, is spending half a year traveling in Europe really not motivating enough? Or are you afraid of delaying graduation? Afraid you won’t get into a good exchange school? Afraid that, after half a year, you still won’t know what you want to do and will fall behind? Maybe the applications and planning feel exhausting. These fears are understandable, but reflecting on them deeply can help you understand yourself better.</p>

<p>Job hunting is the same. It’s easy to blame a “bad market.” But is that really why you can’t find a job?</p>

<p>Facing social pressure when you feel unprepared isn’t easy. The simplest way to cope is to give yourself an excuse. I’m not against using small excuses to navigate socially, but never let them stop you from uncovering the real barriers holding you back.</p>

<p>The moment you stop asking yourself hard questions is often the moment you stop moving forward.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve spoken with a few people, and reflecting on their experiences—and my own—made one thing clear: if you want the life you truly want, you have to keep asking yourself hard questions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The wave came</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2026/01/30/The-wave-came.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The wave came" /><published>2026-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2026/01/30/The%20wave%20came</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2026/01/30/The-wave-came.html"><![CDATA[<p>寫這篇文章時，我很高興我過了 Google 的面試，這篇文章想記錄這段找工作的心路歷程。</p>

<p>過去這段時間，每天起床會收到不同公司的 job alert 和數不清的拒信，在沒有任何消息的時候會懷疑自己的履歷是不是不夠好、還是申請哪個步驟做錯了。每天把每個想去的大公司網頁確認有沒有新開的職缺、到 LinkedIn 把六個小時內的職缺全部投一遍、每天刷十題 Leetcode。到處傳 cold message、在校友會或是各種活動試著多 connect 別人。有拿到面試後試著把 tagged 題全部刷完、每兩天至少約一次模擬面試、在各個論壇找之前考過的題目來練習。永遠都覺得自己還可以準備更多，同時還有學校的課業要顧，回想起來蠻不可思議的，這些枯燥乏味又沒什麼回饋的日常我做了整整一年。</p>

<p>這一年拒絕了好多出去玩的邀請，會覺得現在還是花家裡的錢，不想成為家裡的負擔，同時也會覺得有件該做的事情還沒做到，沒辦法真的盡興地玩。有次跟朋友的爸爸聊到暑假沒有要回台灣，他不經意地說我會不會就像被放掉的風箏一飛就不回來，聽完後也會開始想，家人會不會其實也有這樣的擔心。但我比誰都還要在乎他們，同時也覺得自己沒做到該做到的，憑什麼回去。</p>

<p>對家裡的虧欠也是，在美國真的絕大部分時間都專心在自己身上，打電話通常也報喜不報憂，知道他們想關心我找工作的狀況但又不敢多問，我很想跟他們分享好消息但我還沒做到。偶爾刷題或投工作會覺得喘，走在路上會覺得自己吸不太到氣。回頭審視這些確實有點把自己逼太緊了，不過也知道這來自於我對自己的期許。</p>

<p>市場不好、大公司裁員、政策變來變去，在面對這些自己控制不了的事，慶幸自己有屏蔽掉那些雜訊，盡可能控制好自己能掌控的。第一份工作因為身分關係可能會待一段時間，謝謝自己沒有為現實屈服而放棄理想。在幾次面試被拒絕後，也有誠實地面對自己，確保下一次不再犯同樣的錯，能表現得更好。</p>

<p>接到通過面試的時候，當下有幾秒什麼話都說不出來，那是一種沒有辜負自己、對自己說到做到的感受，真的蠻感動的。去年有寫下 “You’re one year of focus away from people saying you got lucky.” 總算鬆一口氣，不用再時時刻刻覺得自己還沒做到。</p>

<p>找到工作就是一個運氣集結實力的結果，不過這種幸運跟中樂透不一樣，你可以靠你的積極和努力，把幸運的表面積變得越來越大。最重要的就是穩住心態，就像衝浪一樣，隨時把自己準備好，永遠相信下一波浪一定會來。</p>

<p>當你真心渴望某件東西時，整個宇宙都會聯合起來幫助你完成。不管市場多差，還是有人能到達想去的地方。Make that you.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[寫這篇文章時，我很高興我過了 Google 的面試，這篇文章想記錄這段找工作的心路歷程。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2025 Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/2025-Review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2025 Review" /><published>2025-12-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/2025%20Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/2025-Review.html"><![CDATA[<p>這是我第三年做年度回顧。</p>

<p>今年比起去年來說更多的跟自己的事相處，無論是找工作、感情，都花了更多的時間和精力。</p>

<p>從今年初開始認真的找工作，到現在也要一年了，這段時間每天就是瘋狂投工作、修履歷、刷離、認識更多人、傳訊息給陌生人，過程中有面試前幾天被取消、沒找到暑期實習、每天起床打開手機迎接我的是無數的拒信和求職訊息。這些日常到後來我變得能夠享受，就像在打怪一樣，怪物越大英雄越偉大。</p>

<p>我喜歡自己的韌性和始終相信著自己一定做得到，喜歡自己盡力花最大的努力把能掌控的事掌控好，喜歡自己不輕易為現實屈服，期許自己繼續保有這樣的底氣去面對未來的任何挑戰。</p>

<p>明年初有個很想要的公司的最後一輪面試，如果真的找到工作，我會為自己感到驕傲，真的達到為自己設定的目標，然後終於能放下心中的大石頭去想去的各個地方。</p>

<p>出國後我大大的感受到我是個能夠給予愛的人，無論是朋友亦或是感情。我是個幸運的人，被大力的支持著無論做任何事情，出國讀書後對於父母有更深一層的感激，也看到那些他們默默付出愛的方式，這些我都有牢牢的記住。</p>

<p>能夠更好的部分：在說自己相信的事時，不一定要把事情說滿，可以留給空間讓別人去發揮，或許說得太滿、太直接會失去了聽到別人想法的機會 ; 感情上還是太容易把重心放到別人身上，愛不是佔有是選擇。</p>

<p>去年期許自己能夠珍惜自己的時間、珍惜關係、選擇身邊的人，前兩點有用力的做到，至於第三點，這一年放很多時間在自己身上，不太好評估。</p>

<p>新的一年一樣許三個願望：</p>

<ol>
  <li>不要一直設定目標證明自己：有一部分的我想要跑馬拉松跑到特定時間內，然後可以想像達到目標後再去爬到最高的山、潛到最深的海，我希望如果我真的做了是因為我真的享受其中。</li>
  <li>把自己的世界變大：即將要到人生的下個階段，工作除外，還有很多東西值得去探索和體驗。</li>
  <li>適度用力：各種事太容易不小心就投入太多，但物極必反，練習找到最適當的力氣面對生活。</li>
</ol>

<p>如果說人生可以活到八十歲，二十五歲只不過是人生的早上七點半，才正準備迎接這個世界。未來還是有很多的不確定性，比起徬徨更多的是期待接下來的生活。</p>

<p>下一年，結束求學生涯，踏到不同的人生階段，期許自己能夠繼續熱情地擁抱過生活、在快速的步調中學會從容。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[這是我第三年做年度回顧。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Shoulders I Stand On</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The-Shoulders-I-Stand-On.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Shoulders I Stand On" /><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The%20Shoulders%20I%20Stand%20On</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The-Shoulders-I-Stand-On.html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past few years, I often felt more mature than my parents. I can look at problems from different perspectives, face challenges rationally, analyze the pros and cons, and make decisions that are most suitable for us. I have clarity about the path I want to pursue, the life I want to live, and the person I want to become. I have dreams, I take action, and I rarely waste time.</p>

<p>After listening to a podcast, I realized that my parents always tried their best to help me grow in the way they thought was best. Although it might not have been the perfect or ideal way, they ensured that I could stand on their shoulders. This made me feel both guilty and incredibly lucky—to have parents whose efforts and love I can truly feel.</p>

<p>In the future, I would also give everything I have to my children. I might make mistakes, but I can ensure that they will be able to stand on my shoulders and see the world more clearly.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the past few years, I often felt more mature than my parents. I can look at problems from different perspectives, face challenges rationally, analyze the pros and cons, and make decisions that are most suitable for us. I have clarity about the path I want to pursue, the life I want to live, and the person I want to become. I have dreams, I take action, and I rarely waste time.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Richness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Richness" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness.html"><![CDATA[<p>For a long time, when i thought of richness, the first thing came to mind was money. But after a year in Seattle, my perspective has completely changed.</p>

<p>I’ve met so many people who fit the stereotype of being “rich”, working in big tech, able to buy whatever they want, generously tipping without hesitation. And yet, I’ve noticed something important: some of them don’t take care of their health, staying on call late at night or buried in endless workloads. Some are couples who seem disconnected, never wanting to spend time together alone. Others constantly talk about their compensation at social events, indifferent to the people around them—even when it’s clear that others are exhausted by the conversation.</p>

<p>Watching this, I realized that money can give you options, but it cannot replace the fundamental things that make life meaningful. What truly draws me in are the people who are rich in spirit. These are the ones who inspire through curiosity, kindness, creativity, and the courage to live according to their values. Some of them haven’t even begun to earn much money, yet the way they live and the choices they make are already captivating.</p>

<p>I’ve come to understand that the richness I want isn’t about accumulating wealth. It’s about cultivating a life full of meaning, connection, and purpose.</p>

<p>I want to pursue richness in spirit, not just in money.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a long time, when i thought of richness, the first thing came to mind was money. But after a year in Seattle, my perspective has completely changed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kindness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kindness" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I brought my friend’s friends on a tour of Seattle and took them to a café that is one of my mom’s favorites. I could tell how they felt just from their reaction after a sip of coffee. I don’t mean that anyone should pretend to like something, but if I were in her place, I might notice different aspects—like the smoothness, a unique flavor, or even, if the coffee isn’t perfect, the cozy vibe of the café. A thoughtful comment like that can make the host feel appreciated.</p>

<p>Similarly, if someone cooks for you, even if the flavor isn’t exactly your preference, you can highlight something you enjoy and then offer gentle feedback.</p>

<p>I read a book that mentioned how leaving room for others’ contributions is also a form of kindness. For example, if you host a party and don’t require guests to bring food, you can still allow them to bring a gift or let them know they’re welcome to bring something they enjoy, so they feel included and equal.</p>

<p>Kindness often shows up in the small details of behavior, and responding positively to a gift or effort from someone else is itself a way of showing kindness.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I brought my friend’s friends on a tour of Seattle and took them to a café that is one of my mom’s favorites. I could tell how they felt just from their reaction after a sip of coffee. I don’t mean that anyone should pretend to like something, but if I were in her place, I might notice different aspects—like the smoothness, a unique flavor, or even, if the coffee isn’t perfect, the cozy vibe of the café. A thoughtful comment like that can make the host feel appreciated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Feedback Barrier</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The-Feedback-Barrier.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Feedback Barrier" /><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The%20Feedback%20Barrier</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The-Feedback-Barrier.html"><![CDATA[<p>People might not give you feedback for two main reasons:</p>

<ol>
  <li>They feel you won’t listen.</li>
  <li>They feel you won’t change.</li>
</ol>

<p>For the first point, some people ask for feedback but when they receive it, they immediately make excuses like, “I did that because…,” or “That was an exception, normally I wouldn’t do that.” Even worse, some get angry when hearing things they don’t want to hear. Whenever you receive feedback, remember: no excuses.</p>

<p>For the second point, if you give feedback to someone but never see them take action, you might feel they don’t want to change. As a result, you might stop giving feedback, even if you think it’s important. At the end of the day, it’s their life, not yours.</p>

<p>Both points remind me to really listen when I get feedback and act on what I want to change. When people see that, they will feel more comfortable giving honest feedback, and that helps me grow.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[People might not give you feedback for two main reasons:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choosing Pain without suffering</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing-Pain-without-suffering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choosing Pain without suffering" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing%20Pain%20without%20suffering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing-Pain-without-suffering.html"><![CDATA[<p>As a child, when you touched something hot, you felt pain. That pain was information: it taught you it could hurt you.</p>

<p>When I sign up for a marathon, I’m signing up for pain. It’s never easy to push myself again and again, and whether I keep going is up to me.</p>

<p>Over the past year, I’ve realized I actually enjoy most of the pain. I enjoy pushing myself while running and swimming, falling down while skiing, grinding hard while job hunting, and more. There’s a saying: “Pain is inevitable, but suffering is optional.” You can choose pain without choosing suffering.</p>

<p>When I went skiing for the first time, I fell every few steps. It hurt, but it taught me how to adjust. I knew I was learning, and I loved seeing myself grow stronger each time.</p>

<p>Self-discipline is the highest form of self-love. Sometimes, discipline brings pain, but you decide whether to suffer or to embrace the process. If you can learn to manage your suffering and see your scars as beautiful, you will become invincible.</p>

<p>When you feel pain, ask yourself what it’s trying to teach you. If it’s useful, seek the next pain.</p>

<p>You’ll be proud of who you become.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a child, when you touched something hot, you felt pain. That pain was information: it taught you it could hurt you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How soccer shaped me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How-soccer-shaped-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How soccer shaped me" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How%20soccer%20shaped%20me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How-soccer-shaped-me.html"><![CDATA[<p>Soccer has been a part of my life for more than 15 years, ever since I was nine. At that age, most parents just want their kids to stay active or make new friends, and I’m incredibly grateful that my parents chose soccer for me. Looking back, that simple decision shaped not only my childhood but also the person I’ve become.</p>

<p>From elementary school onward, I joined every varsity soccer team except during middle school. At that time, my parents hoped I could balance academics and athletics, so they enrolled me in a special program that focused on both. Unfortunately, that program didn’t include soccer.</p>

<p>Ironically, I had been swimming even longer than I had been playing soccer. But unlike soccer, I never loved it. Swimming felt exhausting and isolating. The pool was cold, and the environment lacked connection. The people I trained with felt more like competitors than teammates. We rarely exchanged tips or encouragement. During practice, our coach often sat by the pool, scrolling through his phone while we swam lap after lap with little guidance.</p>

<p>I remember once, desperate for a break, I pretended to go to the bathroom just to escape the routine. Another time, I tried hiding underwater near the coach to skip a lap, but obviously, it didn’t work. I came up gasping, with tears mixing into the water inside my goggles, and silently finished the lap.</p>

<p>Soccer, on the other hand, brought much more connection, energy, and joy. I still remember how, in elementary school, we would squeeze in training during the longest class breaks. In university, we called each other to plan solo practices, pushing ourselves together to earn a spot in Division One. That shared commitment created a bond that extended far beyond the field.</p>

<p>But the journey was never easy. There were endless repetitions of fundamental drills and physically demanding workouts that pushed us to our limits just like any other sport. It was during those tough sessions that I realized studying actually felt much easier compared to the grit and effort we poured into soccer. And nothing hurt more than giving our all, only to fall short. One memory that still stays with me is the heartbreak of conceding a last-minute equalizer and losing in extra time during a championship game that could have promoted us to Division One.</p>

<p>I never won any major title. But over time, I came to understand that the journey gave me something far more meaningful. The bonds we built through shared struggle have lasted for years. Many of my closest friends today are still the teammates I met back in elementary school. Though we don’t see each other often, whenever we meet, it feels like nothing has changed. The same jokes, the same stories, and the same laughter always bring us back to those good old days.</p>

<p>Looking back, both soccer and swimming taught me lessons I’ll carry for life. Swimming taught me how to compete with myself and strive to improve over time. Soccer taught me the power of teamwork, discipline, and trust. Together, they taught me resilience, focus, and the importance of trusting the process and staying consistent even when things get tough. And most importantly, they taught me to never stop striving to be better.</p>

<p>I may not have collected trophies, but the life lessons I gained along the way are worth far more.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soccer has been a part of my life for more than 15 years, ever since I was nine. At that age, most parents just want their kids to stay active or make new friends, and I’m incredibly grateful that my parents chose soccer for me. Looking back, that simple decision shaped not only my childhood but also the person I’ve become.]]></summary></entry></feed>