<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-29T11:33:21-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Victor Chen</title><subtitle>Just weaving my little corner of the web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Shoulders I Stand On</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The-Shoulders-I-Stand-On.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Shoulders I Stand On" /><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The%20Shoulders%20I%20Stand%20On</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/20/The-Shoulders-I-Stand-On.html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past few years, I often felt more mature than my parents. I can look at problems from different perspectives, face challenges rationally, analyze the pros and cons, and make decisions that are most suitable for us. I have clarity about the path I want to pursue, the life I want to live, and the person I want to become. I have dreams, I take action, and I rarely waste time.</p>

<p>After listening to a podcast, I realized that my parents always tried their best to help me grow in the way they thought was best. Although it might not have been the perfect or ideal way, they ensured that I could stand on their shoulders. This made me feel both guilty and incredibly lucky—to have parents whose efforts and love I can truly feel.</p>

<p>In the future, I would also give everything I have to my children. I might make mistakes, but I can ensure that they will be able to stand on my shoulders and see the world more clearly.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the past few years, I often felt more mature than my parents. I can look at problems from different perspectives, face challenges rationally, analyze the pros and cons, and make decisions that are most suitable for us. I have clarity about the path I want to pursue, the life I want to live, and the person I want to become. I have dreams, I take action, and I rarely waste time.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Richness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Richness" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Richness.html"><![CDATA[<p>For a long time, when i thought of richness, the first thing came to mind was money. But after a year in Seattle, my perspective has completely changed.</p>

<p>I’ve met so many people who fit the stereotype of being “rich”, working in big tech, able to buy whatever they want, generously tipping without hesitation. And yet, I’ve noticed something important: some of them don’t take care of their health, staying on call late at night or buried in endless workloads. Some are couples who seem disconnected, never wanting to spend time together alone. Others constantly talk about their compensation at social events, indifferent to the people around them—even when it’s clear that others are exhausted by the conversation.</p>

<p>Watching this, I realized that money can give you options, but it cannot replace the fundamental things that make life meaningful. What truly draws me in are the people who are rich in spirit. These are the ones who inspire through curiosity, kindness, creativity, and the courage to live according to their values. Some of them haven’t even begun to earn much money, yet the way they live and the choices they make are already captivating.</p>

<p>I’ve come to understand that the richness I want isn’t about accumulating wealth. It’s about cultivating a life full of meaning, connection, and purpose.</p>

<p>I want to pursue richness in spirit, not just in money.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a long time, when i thought of richness, the first thing came to mind was money. But after a year in Seattle, my perspective has completely changed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kindness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kindness" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/Kindness.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I brought my friend’s friends on a tour of Seattle and took them to a café that is one of my mom’s favorites. I could tell how they felt just from their reaction after a sip of coffee. I don’t mean that anyone should pretend to like something, but if I were in her place, I might notice different aspects—like the smoothness, a unique flavor, or even, if the coffee isn’t perfect, the cozy vibe of the café. A thoughtful comment like that can make the host feel appreciated.</p>

<p>Similarly, if someone cooks for you, even if the flavor isn’t exactly your preference, you can highlight something you enjoy and then offer gentle feedback.</p>

<p>I read a book that mentioned how leaving room for others’ contributions is also a form of kindness. For example, if you host a party and don’t require guests to bring food, you can still allow them to bring a gift or let them know they’re welcome to bring something they enjoy, so they feel included and equal.</p>

<p>Kindness often shows up in the small details of behavior, and responding positively to a gift or effort from someone else is itself a way of showing kindness.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I brought my friend’s friends on a tour of Seattle and took them to a café that is one of my mom’s favorites. I could tell how they felt just from their reaction after a sip of coffee. I don’t mean that anyone should pretend to like something, but if I were in her place, I might notice different aspects—like the smoothness, a unique flavor, or even, if the coffee isn’t perfect, the cozy vibe of the café. A thoughtful comment like that can make the host feel appreciated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Feedback Barrier</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The-Feedback-Barrier.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Feedback Barrier" /><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The%20Feedback%20Barrier</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/03/The-Feedback-Barrier.html"><![CDATA[<p>People might not give you feedback for two main reasons:</p>

<ol>
  <li>They feel you won’t listen.</li>
  <li>They feel you won’t change.</li>
</ol>

<p>For the first point, some people ask for feedback but when they receive it, they immediately make excuses like, “I did that because…,” or “That was an exception, normally I wouldn’t do that.” Even worse, some get angry when hearing things they don’t want to hear. Whenever you receive feedback, remember: no excuses.</p>

<p>For the second point, if you give feedback to someone but never see them take action, you might feel they don’t want to change. As a result, you might stop giving feedback, even if you think it’s important. At the end of the day, it’s their life, not yours.</p>

<p>Both points remind me to really listen when I get feedback and act on what I want to change. When people see that, they will feel more comfortable giving honest feedback, and that helps me grow.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[People might not give you feedback for two main reasons:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choosing Pain without suffering</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing-Pain-without-suffering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choosing Pain without suffering" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing%20Pain%20without%20suffering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/Choosing-Pain-without-suffering.html"><![CDATA[<p>As a child, when you touched something hot, you felt pain. That pain was information: it taught you it could hurt you.</p>

<p>When I sign up for a marathon, I’m signing up for pain. It’s never easy to push myself again and again, and whether I keep going is up to me.</p>

<p>Over the past year, I’ve realized I actually enjoy most of the pain. I enjoy pushing myself while running and swimming, falling down while skiing, grinding hard while job hunting, and more. There’s a saying: “Pain is inevitable, but suffering is optional.” You can choose pain without choosing suffering.</p>

<p>When I went skiing for the first time, I fell every few steps. It hurt, but it taught me how to adjust. I knew I was learning, and I loved seeing myself grow stronger each time.</p>

<p>Self-discipline is the highest form of self-love. Sometimes, discipline brings pain, but you decide whether to suffer or to embrace the process. If you can learn to manage your suffering and see your scars as beautiful, you will become invincible.</p>

<p>When you feel pain, ask yourself what it’s trying to teach you. If it’s useful, seek the next pain.</p>

<p>You’ll be proud of who you become.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a child, when you touched something hot, you felt pain. That pain was information: it taught you it could hurt you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work-life Balance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/Work-life-Balance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work-life Balance" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/Work-life%20Balance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/Work-life-Balance.html"><![CDATA[<p>Someone once asked my instructor,
“How can I keep gaining knowledge while working?”</p>

<p>He replied,
“Do you read any books that aren’t required for class? If yes, then you’re already gaining knowledge. If not, then maybe you need to think about it.”</p>

<p>I feel it’s totally the same with work-life balance.</p>

<p>Ask yourself: Do you have balance right now? If yes, keep going. If not, it might be worth reflecting on what you’re chasing.</p>

<p>It often starts with a goal: getting into a good school, then landing a stable job, then earning a better salary, buying a house, getting promoted, even comparing your children’s achievements. There’s always a new carrot dangling in front of you, leading to the next thing, and the next, without end.</p>

<p>It’s easy to get caught in this loop, believing you’ll rest after the “next goal.” But life doesn’t always slow down for you to find balance; you have to create it.</p>

<p>Balance isn’t about doing less or giving up your ambitions. It’s about making space for what matters outside of work, such as your health, your hobbies, your family, your quiet time, and letting these become part of your rhythm, not something you squeeze in when you’re too tired.</p>

<p>Just like reading outside of class shows you’re still learning, taking small steps each day to enjoy life outside of work shows you’re living.</p>

<p>If you’re not feeling balanced, maybe it’s time to ask yourself:
“What is the next carrot I’m chasing, and is it worth it right now?”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Someone once asked my instructor, “How can I keep gaining knowledge while working?”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How soccer shaped me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How-soccer-shaped-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How soccer shaped me" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How%20soccer%20shaped%20me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/How-soccer-shaped-me.html"><![CDATA[<p>Soccer has been a part of my life for more than 15 years, ever since I was nine. At that age, most parents just want their kids to stay active or make new friends, and I’m incredibly grateful that my parents chose soccer for me. Looking back, that simple decision shaped not only my childhood but also the person I’ve become.</p>

<p>From elementary school onward, I joined every varsity soccer team except during middle school. At that time, my parents hoped I could balance academics and athletics, so they enrolled me in a special program that focused on both. Unfortunately, that program didn’t include soccer.</p>

<p>Ironically, I had been swimming even longer than I had been playing soccer. But unlike soccer, I never loved it. Swimming felt exhausting and isolating. The pool was cold, and the environment lacked connection. The people I trained with felt more like competitors than teammates. We rarely exchanged tips or encouragement. During practice, our coach often sat by the pool, scrolling through his phone while we swam lap after lap with little guidance.</p>

<p>I remember once, desperate for a break, I pretended to go to the bathroom just to escape the routine. Another time, I tried hiding underwater near the coach to skip a lap, but obviously, it didn’t work. I came up gasping, with tears mixing into the water inside my goggles, and silently finished the lap.</p>

<p>Soccer, on the other hand, brought much more connection, energy, and joy. I still remember how, in elementary school, we would squeeze in training during the longest class breaks. In university, we called each other to plan solo practices, pushing ourselves together to earn a spot in Division One. That shared commitment created a bond that extended far beyond the field.</p>

<p>But the journey was never easy. There were endless repetitions of fundamental drills and physically demanding workouts that pushed us to our limits just like any other sport. It was during those tough sessions that I realized studying actually felt much easier compared to the grit and effort we poured into soccer. And nothing hurt more than giving our all, only to fall short. One memory that still stays with me is the heartbreak of conceding a last-minute equalizer and losing in extra time during a championship game that could have promoted us to Division One.</p>

<p>I never won any major title. But over time, I came to understand that the journey gave me something far more meaningful. The bonds we built through shared struggle have lasted for years. Many of my closest friends today are still the teammates I met back in elementary school. Though we don’t see each other often, whenever we meet, it feels like nothing has changed. The same jokes, the same stories, and the same laughter always bring us back to those good old days.</p>

<p>Looking back, both soccer and swimming taught me lessons I’ll carry for life. Swimming taught me how to compete with myself and strive to improve over time. Soccer taught me the power of teamwork, discipline, and trust. Together, they taught me resilience, focus, and the importance of trusting the process and staying consistent even when things get tough. And most importantly, they taught me to never stop striving to be better.</p>

<p>I may not have collected trophies, but the life lessons I gained along the way are worth far more.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soccer has been a part of my life for more than 15 years, ever since I was nine. At that age, most parents just want their kids to stay active or make new friends, and I’m incredibly grateful that my parents chose soccer for me. Looking back, that simple decision shaped not only my childhood but also the person I’ve become.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some thoughts @Fred</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Some-thoughts-@Fred.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some thoughts @Fred" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Some%20thoughts%20@Fred</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Some-thoughts-@Fred.html"><![CDATA[<p>最近對人生又多了些感觸，不夠具體能用言語清楚表達，想在這邊看能不能紀錄現在當下的感受。</p>

<p>我喜歡我自己能夠奮不顧身且勇敢的做各種事情、有自己的想法、不太在乎表面的頭銜、有自己的追求、正向、很容易跟各種人聊天社交、能夠讓別人覺得我有在替他們著想、很容易滿足，這些都在來美國後被更加放大。</p>

<p>不過我也看到很多自己還可以做的更好的地方，我執拗、常常講話沒大沒小、做事很急。</p>

<p>在追求自我的同時，希望自己能夠趕快經濟獨立，可以不用依靠別人；也好希望能在想給予的時候就給予，想要大方地對待朋友，不用有什麼顧慮。</p>

<p>後來想想，何其有幸我還有餘裕在追求自己的理想、還能夠為別人想，何其有幸能夠在資源那麼多的環境學習，何其有幸能夠不愁吃穿還能在咖啡廳裡打這些想這些。謹記著不管怎麼樣，要無悔地過生活，要用力地愛著自己和身旁重要的人們，同時請繼續嚴格的對待自己，做個自己也會嚮往的大人。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[最近對人生又多了些感觸，不夠具體能用言語清楚表達，想在這邊看能不能紀錄現在當下的感受。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">寧鳴而死，不默而生</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/22/%E5%AF%A7%E9%B3%B4%E8%80%8C%E6%AD%BB-%E4%B8%8D%E9%BB%98%E8%80%8C%E7%94%9F.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="寧鳴而死，不默而生" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/22/%E5%AF%A7%E9%B3%B4%E8%80%8C%E6%AD%BB%EF%BC%8C%E4%B8%8D%E9%BB%98%E8%80%8C%E7%94%9F</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/22/%E5%AF%A7%E9%B3%B4%E8%80%8C%E6%AD%BB-%E4%B8%8D%E9%BB%98%E8%80%8C%E7%94%9F.html"><![CDATA[<p>如果身旁有人做出了超過自己底線的事，還會繼續跟他當朋友嗎？</p>

<p>身邊陸續的一些事件，不禁讓我反思自己應對的情緒以及方式，藉此更了解自己也知道哪些部分可以再進步。</p>

<p>有朋友說會當在有利益可圖的時候，會以比較柔軟的手段面對自己覺得不對的事。但這是我想要的嗎？該因為自己的短期利益而對於自己覺得 ”不正確“ 的事默不吭聲嗎？</p>

<p>沈默也是一種選擇，代表著對於接收到的事件的一種默認，就好比投票一樣。我認為目前的我會選擇疏離這種踩到我底線的朋友，畢竟朋友在質不在量。你是五個身旁最靠近的朋友的平均，還是把自己的實力好好提升，這樣就不需要因為外在的因素改變自己，身邊的人是自己認可的也能更踏實。</p>

<p>不過如何柔軟是個我需要學習的課題。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[如果身旁有人做出了超過自己底線的事，還會繼續跟他當朋友嗎？]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I cannot slow down @Green Lake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/02/Why-I-cannot-slow-down-@green-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I cannot slow down @Green Lake" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/02/Why%20I%20cannot%20slow%20down%20@green%20lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/02/Why-I-cannot-slow-down-@green-lake.html"><![CDATA[<p>這幾天媽媽來西雅圖找我，這幾天我也發現我好像慢不下來了。</p>

<p>一個人去跑步的時候，每次速度一放慢就會覺得對不起自己，每次都應該要盡全力才對；跟媽媽講話如果她答非所問就會覺得講話應該要更有效率的表達。</p>

<p>也許是因為想要找工作、體驗美國生活、好好修課、練英文、學生活技能、做些自己能夠做到的 pay back，所以必須善用所有的時間才能最大化生活。但在衝刺狀態下要記得欣賞沿路的風景，更要提醒自己面對身旁的人的態度。</p>

<p>學會慢下，有時候慢慢來比較快。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Other" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[這幾天媽媽來西雅圖找我，這幾天我也發現我好像慢不下來了。]]></summary></entry></feed>